Inventory of the Philip Lightfoot Papers 1765-1860
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Papers Relating to Accounts Collected by Philip Lightfoot. (Box-folder 3:9-10 and 4:11-12)
  - Wright (Morgan), 1807-1809., 3 items. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - R.H. Yancey, executor of Yancey ( ), 1805., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)
  Series 5: Legal Papers
- Legal Papers, 1788-1847, n.d. (Box-folder 4:13 and 5:14)
  - Botts (Daniel W.) and wife to Armistead Botts, 1842., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Trust deed to a tract of land in Rappahannock County, Virginia, for the benefit of William Slaughter.
  - Brown (Gideon H.), assignee of Jarrett Menefree, and Philip Lightfoot vs. David Mason et al., 1840-1844., 8 items. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Suit in Rappahannock County.
  - Burt (Lewis). Estate, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Camp (John) to Samuel Clayton, n.d., 1 piece, mutilated. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Release of lien on slaves.
  - Clagett (Henry) to Philip Lightfoot, 1805., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Bill of sale for a Negro slave.
  - Clayton (James B.) to Philip Lightfoot, 1828., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Deed to a tract of land in Culpeper County, Virginia.
  - Covington (John), assignee of Philip Lightfoot who was assignee of [?] R. Farish, vs. William Porter, 1830., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Suit in Culpeper County.
  - Cowne (Robert) vs. Pendleton & Brown, 1804., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Croudson (Samuel) vs. Thomas Camp, 1798., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Croudson (Samuel) vs. Thomas Eldredge and William Hill, 1798., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Croudson (Samuel) vs. Robert Latham, Jr., 1799., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Culpeper County.
  - Drew (Hannah), 1806-1828, 25 items. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Estate, including extract of will.
  - Dulaney (William H.) vs. David Jameson, 1802., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Dunbar vs. Walker, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Fairfax (Lord Thomas) to Robert Coleman, 1748., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Quitrent deed to a tract of land in Orange County, Virginia.
  - Gainer (John) vs. Robert Cowne, 1804., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Gaines vs. Philip Slaughter, administrator of Philip Clayton, 1818. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Suit.
  - Gaw (Robert) vs. John C. Williams, 1811-1813., 5 items. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Suits in Culpeper County.
  - Griffin (Zachariah) et al. vs. Larkin G. Nalle et al., 1817., 3 items. (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Haywood vs. Martha Edzard, 1795., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Adam Hunter and Abner Vernon, executors of Hunter (James) vs. Robert Coleman et al., 1790-1791., 2 items. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Suit in Richmond, Virginia.
  - Jameson (John) to Hannah Drew, 1824., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Deed to a tract of land in Fairfax County, Virginia.
  - Jones (Gabriel), 1781., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Estate.
  - Lampton (Henry) vs. Cuth. Payton, 1788., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Suit in Orange County, Virginia.
  - Lee (Daniel), assignee of William Eve who was assignee of John Wright vs. Elliot Rucker, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Suit in Madison County, Virginia.
  - Thomas B. Smith, guardian of Lightfoot (Fanny and John J.) to Edward Lightfoot, 1847., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Power of Attorney.
  - Lightfoot (Goodrich) to Philip Lightfoot, 1805., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Lightfoot (Philip) vs. John Covington, executor of Robert Slaughter, 1842., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Suit in Culpeper County, Virginia.
  - Lightfoot (Philip), 1839., 2 items. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Will.
  - Lightfoot (Philip), 1850., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Declaration of Philip Lightfoot's military service in 1812, for the purpose of obtaining bounty land.
  - Lightfoot (Philip) and Richard H. Field to Daniel T. Strother, 1828., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Power of attorney for sale of a tract of land in Kentucky.
  - Long (Armistead) to Philip Lightfoot and Richard H. Field, 1829., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Indemnity bond.
  - Robert Jones for Marshall (James) vs. Pierce Perry, 1821., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Overton Cosby and James Ross, executors of Mills (James) vs. Patrick Home, William Clayton Williams, and Philip Lightfoot, 1801., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Ming (George) and George Good, 1800., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Agreement concerning the sale of a slave.
  - Mole (George) vs. Henry Camp, 1799., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Nalle vs. Burton, 1820., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Nalle (Mary L.) et al. to Philip Lightfoot, 1846., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:13)
    Deed to a tract of land in Culpeper County.
  - Pittenger (Henry), 1788-1811., 12 items. (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Pittenger (Richard), 1805., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Pittenger (Richard and Henry), 1797-1817., 7 items. (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Porter (Mary) vs. George Calvert and William Thorn, 1826-1828., 2 items. (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Ransdell (Stephen) vs. James W. Davies [?], 1818., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Reintzel (Andrew) vs. William Bayly, Jr., and Charles Beatty, 1791., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Suit in the High Court of Chancery of Maryland.
  - Richardson et al. vs. Turner, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Roberts (Benjamin), n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Estate, Culpeper County, Virginia.
  - Susanna Roberts, administratrix of Roberts (Joseph) vs. Joseph Roberts, George Roberts, Benjamin Roberts, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Roebuck (Robert) vs. John Fry, administrator of William Waddle, n.d., 2 items. (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Rootes (Philip) and others to James Hunter, 1765., 1 piece, copy. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Deed to a tract of land in Culpeper County, Virginia, 1765.
  - Rosson (Elijah) vs. Samuel K. Bradford and John Lewis, 1810-1812., 5 items. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Suit in Albemarle County, Virginia.
  - Shore (Thomas) vs. John Boufield et al., 1792., 1 piece, newspaper clipping. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Suit in High Court of Chancery, Richmond.
  - Slaughter (Philip) to Philip Lightfoot, 1841., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Deed of sale covering lands in Culpeper County, Virginia, and slaves and personal property devised by Marshall Petty, deceased, to John S. Petty.
  - Slaughter (Philip) and Samuel Slaughter to Robert Slaughter and James Slaughter, 1795., 1 piece, copy. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Deed conveying certain Negroes and personal property in trust for the benefit of James and Susannah Slaughter.
  - Slaughter (Robert) and Reuben Slaughter to Francis T. Lightfoot, 1831., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Trust deed covering three tracts of land in Culpeper County, Virginia.
  - Stanard (John) to Philip Lightfoot, 1819., 1 piece, mutilated. (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Stevens (Gilly), 1820-1831., 19 items. (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Strother (Jeremiah), 1814., 1 piece, copy. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Court order directing Edward Stevens and David Jameson, commissioners, to convey two tracts of land in Culpeper County, Virginia, to Jeremiah Strother.
  - Strother (William), 1802., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Memorandum of suits against H. Dod and Nimrod Berry, Spotsylvania County, Virginia.
  - Thompson (Garland) vs. John Stevens, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Vowles (Zachariah) et al. to Uriel Mallory, Jr., 1811., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Deed to a tract of land in Madison County, Virginia.
  - Walker (James, Jr.) vs. Joseph Brock and Beverley Stubblefield, 1802., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Suit in Fredericksburg District Court.
  - Weedon (Augustine) vs. Joshua Woodrow, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Williams (Isaac H.) vs. John Breedlove, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Williams (John C.), 1803., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Report of a jury on possible injury to property due to the proposal of John C. Williams to raise his mill dam on Cedar Run, Culpeper County, 1803, not signed.
  - Williams (William C.) and wife to Philip Lightfoot, 1801., 1 piece, mutilated. (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Williams (William C.) and wife to Philip Lightfoot, 1803., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Wise (Cuthburt) to Philip Lightfoot, 1804., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Bill of sale for a Negro boy.
  - Memoranda of suits., 4 items. (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Unidentified and incomplete papers, 8 items. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Including one surveyor's plat.
  Series 6: Papers of James L. Markham
- Papers of James L. Markham, 1801-1819, n.d. (Box-folder 5:15)
  - Letters, 1801-1815. (Box-folder 5:15)
    chronologically.
    - George Scott, at Beaver Creek, Barren County, to James L. Markham, 25 October 1801. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - McStewart & Co., at Fredericksburg, to James L. Markham, at Madison Court House, Virginia, 14 May 1807. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - William McDonald, at Baltimore, to James L. Markham, at Madison Court House, Virginia, 7 May 1808. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - William Kenner, at New Orleans, to James Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 7 May, 1808. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - Lott & Ray, at New York, to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 6 October 1810. (Box-folder 5:15)
      An Account appears on the same page.
    - Thomas Ward, at Fredericksburg, to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, 26 October 1810. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - William Kenner, at Philadelphia, to James Markham, at New York, 2 November 1810. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - James W. Breedlove, at New York, to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, November 1810. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - Isaac Winston to James L. Markham, at Fairfax, Culpeper County, Virginia, 6 December 1810. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - James W. Breedlove, at New Orleans, to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 28 December 1810. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - James W. Breedlove, at Port Gibson, Mississippi, to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 22 January 1811. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - William Kenner, at New Orleans, to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 1 February 1811. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - James W. Breedlove, at Gibson Port [i.e., Port Gibson, Mississippi], to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 14 February 1811. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - James W. Breedlove, at Gibson Port [i.e., Port Gibson, Mississippi], to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 21 March 1811. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - James W. Breedlove, at Port Gibson, to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 29 April 1811. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - James W. Breedlove, at Port Gibson, Mississippi Territory, to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 22 May 1811. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - A. B. Bradford, at Greenville, Mississippi, to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 11 June 1811. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - James W. Breedlove, at Port Gibson, to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 25 June-23 July 1811. (Box-folder 5:15)
      Included are letters for the following dates: 25 June, 9 July, 16 July, 23 July 1811.
    - J. Whitehurst, at Gibson Port [i.e., Port Gibson, Mississippi], to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 30 July 1811. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - Lambert & Johnes, at Philadelphia, to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 10 August 1811. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - Worrell & Jennings, at Philadelphia, to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 16 January 1812., Mutilated. (Box-folder 5:15)
      Three accounts appear on the same sheet.
    - Lambert & Johnes, at Philadelphia, to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 14 November 1812. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - James W. Breedlove, at Port Gibson, Mississippi, to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 5 January 1813. (Box-folder 5:15)
      An account of James Tutt with Markham and Breedlove appears on the same sheet.
    - Worrell, Jennings & Co., at Philadelphia, to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 9 February 1815. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - W. S[?] Stone to James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, n.d. (Box-folder 5:15)
      Mutilated.
  - Miscellaneous, 1803-1819. (Box-folder 5:15)
    alphabetically.
    - Accounts, 1803-1819., 53 items. (Box-folder 5:15)
    - Broadside, advertising goods for sale by James L. Markham, 1810., 2 copies, one mutilated. (Box-folder 5:15)
  Series 7: Papers of Samuel Porter
- Papers of Samuel Porter, 1811-1827. (Box-folder 6:16)
  - Letters, 1811-1816. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - A general letter of recommendation from William M. Thompson, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 26 Spetember 1811. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - James Vass, at Falmouth, Stafford County, Virginia, to Samuel Porter, at Culpeper Court House, 30 October 1811. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - Tilmon Porter, at Washington, to his brother, Samuel Porter, at Falmouth, 18 November-6 December 1811. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - James Vass to W. Porter, 28 December 1811. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - Tilmon Porter, at Washington, to Samuel Porter, at Falmouth, 23 January 1812. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - John Miller, Culpeper County, Virginia, to Samuel Porter, at Falmouth, 4 February 1812. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - Tilmon Porter, at Washington, to Samuel Porter, at Falmouth, 4 February 1812. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, to Samuel Porter, at Falmouth, 5 February 1812. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - William Porter to his son, Samuel Porter, at Falmouth, 10 March 1812., Mutilated. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - James L. Markham, at Culpeper Court House, to Samuel Porter, at Falmouth, 21 July 1812. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - Tilmon Porter, at Washington, to Samuel Porter, at Falmouth, 6 October 1812. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - William LeMunday, at Washington, to Samuel Porter, at Falmouth, 28 October 1812. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - James Vass, at Falmouth, to Samuel Porter, at Fredriktown [Frederickton], Sasafras Creek, Maryland, 25 March 1813. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - [?], at Baltimore, to Samuel Porter, at Fredriktown [Frederickton], head of Sassafrass, 2 April 1813. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - James Vass, at Falmouth, to Samuel Porter, at Frederickton, Elkton, Maryland, 12 April 1813. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - John Moody, at Cantwells' Bridge, DE, to Samuel Porter, at Trenton, New Jersey, 27 April 1813. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - John Goddard, at Philadelphia, to Samuel Porter, at Trenton, New Jersey, 14 May 1813. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - James Vass, at Falmouth, to Samuel Porter, at Baltimore, Maryland, 3 November 1813. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - "An Old Acquaintance" to [?], 8 January 1814. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - James Vass to Samuel Porter, at Hartwood, Stafford County, Virginia, 30 March 1814. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - Joseph B. Redd, at Fredericksburg, to Samuel Porter, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 29 June 1815. (Box-folder 6:16)
      An account appears on the same sheet.
    - Worrell, Jennings & Co., at Philadelphia, to Samuel Porter, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 28 September 1815. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - William Ferguson to Samuel Porter, 2 January 1816. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - Worrell, Jennings & Co., at Philadelphia, to Samuel Porter, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 6 January 1816. (Box-folder 6:16)
      This letter, written on a printed circular, includes a copy of a letter from Worrell, Jennings & Co., to Samuel Porter, 11 December 1815.
    - Phil Chew, Jr., at Nottingham, MD, to Samuel Porter, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 17 January 1816. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - Drummond Wilburn, at Horntown, Accomac County, Virginia, to Samuel Porter, at Culpeper Court House, 16 February 1816. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - W. P. Dunnington to Samuel Porter. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - D. Grinnan, at Falmouth, Virginia, to Samuel Porter, at Hartwood, Stafford, County, Virginia. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - James Vass to Samuel Porter., Mutilated. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - [?], at Washington, to Samuel Porter, at Falmouth., Mutilated. (Box-folder 6:16)
  - Accounts, 1815-1816. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - Accounts, 1815-1816. (Box-folder 6:16)
  - Legal papers, 181826-1827. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - Baylis (John) to James Porter. Trust deed covering a tract of land in Culpeper County, Virginia, 1826., 1 item. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - Porter (James) to Philip Lightfoot. Trust deed covering a tract of land in Culpeper County, Virginia, 1827., 1 item. (Box-folder 6:16)
  Series 8: Papers of Merrick Starr
- Papers of Merrick Starr, 1789-1808. (Box-folder 6:17)
  - Invoices and receipts, 1797-1801., 3 items. (Box-folder 6:17)
  - Fee and tax bills and receipts of the clerks and sheriffs of Culpeper County, 1789-1807., 39 items. (Box-folder 6:17)
  - Receipts for taxes paid on carriages, 1796-1799., 3 items. (Box-folder 6:17)
  - Licenses of Merrick Starr, merchant, 1798-1808., 11 items. (Box-folder 6:17)
  - Tax bills of Enos Ellis, 1797-1801., 4 items. (Box-folder 6:17)
  - One cover. (Box-folder 6:17)
  Series 9: Other papers
- Other papers, 1791-1817. (Box-folder 6:18-19)
  Alphabetically by records creator, unknown and fragments at the end.
  - American Republican Society of the United States, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 6:18)
    Articles of association.
  - Culpeper County, 1791., 1 item. (Box-folder 6:18)
    Petition of the citizens of Culpeper County to the House of Delegates requesting that the county be divided.
  - Lightfoot (Philip), 1795., 1 item. (Box-folder 6:18)
    Recommendation for the position of deputy to a county clerk.
  - Lightfoot (Philip), 1801., 1 item. (Box-folder 6:18)
    Certificate of residence in Culpeper County.
  - Lightfoot (Philip), 1809-1815., 2 items. (Box-folder 6:18)
    Two memorandum books containing personal accounts and accounts collected for clients.
  - Lightfoot (Philip)., 16 items. (Box-folder 6:18)
    Legal notes and forms.
  - Lightfoot (Richardi)., 1 item. (Box-folder 6:18)
    Photograph of a portrait, (1562-1625).
  - Russell (Benjamin D.), 1817., 1 item. (Box-folder 6:18)
    Obituary in the handwriting of Philip Lightfoot.
  - Stevens (Edward) and Thomas Eldridge, 1793., 1 item. (Box-folder 6:18)
    Request for membership in the Stevensburg Lodge.
  - Virginia, 1792., 1 piece (3 printed pages). (Box-folder 6:18)
    Acts of the legislature.
  - Wigginton (John), n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 6:18)
    Certificate of office as justice of the peace.
  - A prayer., 1 piece. (Box-folder 6:18)
  - An inventory of slaves and personal property of an unknown person. n.d., 1 piece. (Box-folder 6:18)
  - A memorandum concerning slaves. n.d., 1 piece. (Box-folder 6:18)
  - A list of articles to be purchased. n.d., 1 piece. (Box-folder 6:18)
  - Two fragments of newspapers., 2 pieces. (Box-folder 6:18)
  - Two photographs and postcards., 5 pieces. (Box-folder 6:18)
  - Fragments of 9 papers. (Box-folder 6:19)
  - Other fragments. (Box-folder 6:19)
  - Covers. (Box-folder 6:19)